all right first a caveat I'm in no way
saying that we will own Facebook just
what Facebook would look like if it was
designed for our purpose instead of for
profit so what we would have in common
for something we created together that
makes Facebook amazing is there the
number of people that are on there if we
have a fraction of that number of people
we can do amazing things and change the
world
also the seamless beauty and simplicity
of Facebook that it's basically anyone
can use it but it's also really
technical like there is a lot of it
costs them millions and hundreds of
billions of dollars to create that I
think we can create it for much cheaper
and it can be even better when we tap
into our essence but that's like a whole
other that's a whole other one so for me
anything like social media that we
create this Facebook it's it's three
different things which are I'm there to
find people projects and information the
thing that we would create together
that's kind of what I'm on Facebook for
is well though there aren't projects I
can find there's groups and so projects
groups are kind of the same thing so for
information I get a lot of information
from Facebook because I scroll through
it and then click on the the blog posts
but it's not designed to give us
accurate information it's designed to
keep us there it's designed to give to
be confrontational so the more I'm gonna
post something that's gonna get angry or
likes and loves the more the people are
gonna want to comment on it the better
it is for Facebook so it doesn't make
sense for there for them to go and then
correct information that's not their
point so I can they know they know who
saw it they'd have that in their
algorithm they have that in their
information like hey this many people
read that blog post off of Facebook now
we found out that was inaccurate and
wrong they don't send you something to
say by the way that in that video you
watched actually here's all the
inaccurate things in it we can do that
we can actually have information if it's
the purpose of what we're doing be more
usable be more trustworthy have one
space that's like here's all of the
choreograph all the correlated data and
information on on anti backs and backs
on flat
earth and and and stun so that you're
not having the same debate over and over
again there can be one space that has
that that more information if that's
something that we want to do I see any
project we make together to have a
getting off topic I have way too many
notes here the other thing is people so
Facebook is designed for very surface
level and be as type interactions where
it's like all other people are looking
all their best lives meet on vacation it
doesn't showcase because they're
choosing not to showcase their their bad
side the you know the family photos you
don't take a picture of the tantrum five
minutes later and post it and so we can
design something that is designed to
have deeper connections if that's what
we want something that's designed not
just to find your people so the people
that like oh you went to high school
with these people that's still an
amazing option to have but instead of
that I want to be connected with people
there's no chance of me meeting except
for your your technology because we like
the same things debate on the same
things it can be like by the way we
found a bunch of use out there want to
get together have a book club want to
have a project together that we can
design it to help people find people
that they have stuff in common with
instead of because there is no money in
that or there I'm sure there is
somewhere but like the money is in the
the confrontation to keep you there
longer so that you could they can give
you more arcanine because of their
business model we also I love Facebook
it's attributed to my lives in its
groups which is what I see
finding projects and doing stuff that's
actually like creating things in the
world but the groups I'm part of that
are very meaningful I've parenting
groups I'm part of as well as for my
various disabilities and conditions I
have different different groups I'm part
of and both of those things Facebook or
it works adequately for but it's not
designed for it like the same there's in
exception in the parenting group your
kid has an earache and 20 other people
that week I've asked about the earache
and you could go and look for that but
it's not and we do would you go and look
for those things then there's also like
like hey your kid has a rash what can
you do for the rash
can be Corie Corie information that was
already brought together by every other
person who's asked that and then had
feedback in like yes I tried that and it
didn't work and I tried that it did work
but there's also like right my kid has a
rash I need you to look at this exact
one I want you to look at my situation
so it doesn't mean that just because the
informations out there you can no longer
share your story it just means that
there's also that information so you can
say hey I don't know what you want to
use in this situation which one of you
use and then it's back in the system in
there's information in the backend but
it's not designed to like bring events
together in a way that would be
meaningful where it's like okay here's
where everyone's located did you know
you have five of these people in this
parenting group that are within like ten
blocks of you you guys could get
together on a Wednesday you can even
like know your schedule like Facebook
kind of knows your schedule knows what
you like knows what you don't like but
it can't choreograph your life because
that would be creepy if we designed it
to do that and absolutely I mean it's
maybe still be a little creepy when
we're still in our current culture but
as we find people that we mesh with and
find groups that we work well together
with we can create social media that's
designed with project management works
people through a project works people
through people management so when you
have conflict conflicts within your
group that you can actually work through
them we can design it so that there's
less admin needed because if you have
rules they're just concrete in place for
it's like okay you can't post about this
topic you're posting about this topic
you're just not allowed to unless it
goes to you're like no it's it's
borderline I think we should be able to
it can go to a to a jury of your peers
and have it go to ten people and be like
nope that breaks the rules no you can't
post that we can create something that
we want to spend time on and when we're
spending time on it it is bringing us
joy in a real way and it's contributing
to the world in a real way because it's
designed for that if we design for
purpose instead of profit and we have
the tools to be able to collaborate it's
be able to find people find projects
find groups that are meaningful have
information that's accessible there's
basically no problem we can't solve and
nothing that humanity can't do when they
band together in that way doesn't mean
all is 7.5 billion people it's like
right we're creating a park everyone
also how to create in a park in the city
had to go through these steps we don't
have to refigure out those steps we know
city council we know who to contact on
it because other people have already
done it and put that together so it's
finding people that and working on
projects than just meaningful to you and
I already talked about this for an hour
on a different stream that will may
never be published amarty a seven minute
so I'm gonna and that now and this is a
topic I'm gonna be sitting and thinking
about and even go on periscope and do
for some more time now see you tomorrow